<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="_wl_shared_buffer">

    <copyright>
        Copyright © 2015 Jolla, Ltd.

        Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute, and sell this
        software and its documentation for any purpose is hereby granted
        without fee, provided that the above copyright notice appear in
        all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission
        notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name of
        the copyright holders not be used in advertising or publicity
        pertaining to distribution of the software without specific,
        written prior permission.  The copyright holders make no
        representations about the suitability of this software for any
        purpose.  It is provided "as is" without express or implied
        warranty.

        THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS
        SOFTWARE, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
        FITNESS, IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
        SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES
        WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN
        AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION,
        ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF
        THIS SOFTWARE.
    </copyright>

    <interface name="_wl_shared_buffer" version="1">
        <description summary="A buffer shared from the compositor to a client">
            A _wl_shared_buffer is similar to a wl_buffer, but works in the opposite
            direction, from the compositor to the client. The compositor can create
            a _wl_shared_buffer using a factory such as _wl_shm_shared_buffer_pool
            and send it to the client via some event. The client can then read the
            content of the buffer and use it.
            When the client does not need to access the buffer anymore it should call
            the release request.
        </description>

        <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
            <description summary="Destroy the buffer">
                The destroy request destroys the _wl_shared_buffer object and notifies
                the compositor about it. This request should only be called by the
                factory that created this object, when notified to do so.
                This request should not be called when the user does not need to access
                the content anymore, use the release request instead.
            </description>
        </request>

        <request name="release">
            <description summary="Release the buffer">
                This request notifies the compositor that the client does not need to
                access the content of the buffer anymore. The client should not attempt
                to read from the buffer after calling this request, else artifacts may
                appear.
                The compositor may decide to destroy this buffer object after receiving
                this request.
            </description>
        </request>
    </interface>

    <interface name="_wl_shm_shared_buffer_pool" version="1">
        <description summary="A factory for shm based _wl_shared_buffer">
            The _wl_shm_shared_buffer_pool interface is a factory for _wl_shared_buffer,
            using shared memory data. A new buffer is created via the new_buffer event,
            but must be sent to the client via another event not defined in this extension,
            akin to wl_surface::attach.
        </description>

        <event name="new_buffer">
            <description summary="Advertize a new buffer">
                This event notifies the client of a new _wl_shared_buffer object.
                The data in the buffer can be read by mmapping the given fd, starting
                at the given offset.
                The format of the buffer is guaranteed to be a valid wl_shm buffer format,
                and one of the format advertized by the wl_shm.format event.
            </description>
            <arg name="handle" type="new_id" interface="_wl_shm_shared_buffer_handle"/>
            <arg name="buffer" type="new_id" interface="_wl_shared_buffer"/>
            <arg name="fd" type="fd" summary="The fd of the mmapped file"/>
            <arg name="width" type="int" summary="The width of the buffer"/>
            <arg name="height" type="int" summary="The height of the buffer"/>
            <arg name="stride" type="int" summary="The stride of the buffer, in bytes"/>
            <arg name="format" type="int" summary="The format of the buffer"/>
            <arg name="offset" type="int" summary="The offset of the buffer in the data"/>
        </event>
    </interface>

    <interface name="_wl_shm_shared_buffer_handle" version="1">
        <description summary="A handle for a _wl_shared_buffer">
            This interface is helper interface used by _wl_shm_shared_buffer_pool and
            referencing a _wl_shared_buffer object.
        </description>

        <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
            <description summary="Destroy this object">
                This request should only be called alongside the _wl_shared_buffer.destroy
                request on the referenced _wl_shared_buffer object, only after receiving
                the destroyed event.
            </description>
        </request>

        <event name="destroyed">
            <description summary="Ask the client to destroy the handle">
                The destroyed event is sent by the compositor when the buffer is used no
                more and should be destroyed. The event is guaranteed to never be called
                before the client calls _wl_shared_buffer.release on the buffer associated
                with this handle, and the compositor may send this event after receiving
                the release request on the buffer.
            </description>
        </event>
    </interface>

</protocol>
